In this world...
Is the destiny of mankind controlled by some transcendental entity or law?
Is it like the hand of God hovering above?
At least it is true...
...that man has no control, even over his own will.
I want you to join us, Guts!
Acting so friendly after you stabbed me...
What do you want?
To settle this with our swords...
All right...
I rather enjoy settling things by force...
Griffith!
No matter what, I will have what I want.
I've had enough of you acting so stuck up...
It makes me sick!
Feel no shame about shape
Weather changes their phrase
Even mother will show you another way
So put your glasses on
Nothing will be wrong
There's no blame. There's no fame
It's up to you
The first words should be found
Whatever holds you back
I...
...can...
I can get it off
Tell me what...
Tell me what you want
I don't know why...
Don't know why...
Don't know why you're afraid
Tell me what...
Tell me what you'd say
I don't know why...
Don't know why...
Too late...
It's too late
First Battle
Griffith!
He's something else...
I bet I could split steel with this sword...
...but he easily evades each blow...
...and just uses one arm
to handle his narrow blade!
He's a great fighter!
I could suspend this duel until you've
recovered completely, if you like.
Shut up!
I'll win!
I'll definitely beat him!
Faster!
Stronger!
The kid is challenging Griffith again.
He didn't learn his lesson at all!
Kill him!
Corkus, stop it!
What?
It's Griffith's orders!
You must not bother them!
I will take this opportunity to kill him.
Move!
When did you become leader, Corkus?
Griffith's orders are absolute.
I've got him!
It's settled...
I like the way you fight.
You'll go to any length
to defeat your opponent.
However, you can't wield
your sword unless I move.
What do you say?
I wouldn't mind if you'd rather we desist.
You talk too much. It's annoying.
Let me tell you something.
In a battle, your mouth...
...is to be used like this!
Griffith!
I've never seen Griffith
knocked to the ground like that!
Do you like the taste of your own blood?
I bet you've never had
that fancy face beaten in!
He did it!
You struck me quite soundly...
But this is the end.
Admit defeat amenably
or have your shoulder joint dislocated.
It doesn't matter to me...
You bastard...
Way to go!
That's our Griffith!
Yeah, that's Griffith for you!
You really are the best.
You loser!
You look pathetic, have you lost your nerve?
Griffith?
Now...
...you are mine.
Do you mean it?
He is a member of ours from now on!
Yeah!
It's so strange...
Griffith has never,
ever said such kind words...
...to anyone!
They've been nicknamed
the Grim Reapers of the Battlefield...
...since they're
seemingly invincible in battle.
We do not need to worry
ourselves about them...
...since they are
a subsidiary of the Midland army.
Besides, mercenaries
are merely cannon fodder.
But what if they gain power
and earn the king's trust?
We would face the loss of
our prestige, honor, and pride.
Indeed...
This is irritating!
I was beaten...
...completely!
It's almost a joke!
He...
...talks openly, and smiles
like some innocent kid...
But...
...he dislocated my shoulder
joint cleanly, without hesitation...
...just like plucking off a doll's arm...
Damn it!
Who the hell is he?
Are you serious about killing him, Corkus?
Sheesh!
Don't chicken out at the last moment.
There are seven of us!
You said you didn't like him either, right?
Don't forget he killed Dan.
But he's so strong and skilled.
On top of that, Griffith...
Don't worry.
We'll catch him off guard.
Plus, he's injured and
can't possibly lift his sword.
We'll convince Griffith that the kid escaped...
...after we dump his body in the woods.
This bunch will be no problem compared to him...
Sam, you go first!
Again?
You never go first.
You better not do it.
C-Casca.
He is still far beyond your skill, even injured.
I'll see about that.
Go back to your tent like a good boy, Corkus.
Casca, why are you trying to save him?
Oh, I see.
You lay together for two nights...
No wonder you have some feelings for him...
If you say anything like that ever again...
...I'll chop your head off.
J-Just kidding...
I'm kidding.
Let's go.
It looks like I owe you two...
I should thank you at least.
You're mistaken...
I just acted on Griffith's orders.
Otherwise, I don't give a damn about you.
I hope you drop dead
in battle as soon as you can.
Our foes' base is on the hill
and manned by 2,000 soldiers.
Our job is to burn the provisions and
other supplies stored behind the hill.
Theoretically, they'll fortify the front
of the hill in case of night attacks.
So we...
...will detour along the river and
attempt a surprise attack on their rear.
When we accomplish our goal,
we'll take the shortest route back...
...right through the midst of their forces.
Through the enemy?
Any backup?
None.
It seems they can't afford
to send units for a night attack.
They're just a bunch of cowards.
The rear guard will be...
Guts...
I want you to do it.
You'll help your fellow soldiers escape...
...holding off hundreds of cavalrymen...
...on a straight road in the woods.
Can you manage?
It's an order, isn't it?
It is.
Griffith is trying to put
the kid's skill to the test.
Poor guy, I doubt he'll
make it through in one piece.
He might try to sneak away.
That's not it!
Griffith wouldn't give him such
an important job just as a test...
Griffith truly counts on him.
Now I don't even have to bother killing him.
We're marching in the river, not going along it.
Either way, the enemy won't predict...
...us making a surprise attack
by traveling up such a rapid stream.
In addition, this gale...
...will drown out the noise of our march.
Then we'll set the fire windward...
...when we attack from behind.
Everything's been calculated, huh...
It's freezing.
Lookout duty on such a creepy night...
Unlike us, even wolves wouldn't go out tonight.
T-The enemy?
W-Why are they coming from that direction?
E-Enemy raid!
An enemy raid?
Set the fires!
They set fire to the gunpowder!
Don't stop to play with them!
Break through in a single rush!
Move double file!
Clear out!
General!
The gale is fanning
the flames towards the base!
Damn!
Take the heavy cavalry to the front!
Allowing our base to be
destroyed by mere mercenaries...
...is a disgrace to us knights!
It's amazing!
I have never been part of
such an efficient raid before...
Now it's my job to take care of the rest!
Get out of here!
I-I will!
Follow me...
Come on, keep up!
Good job, Griffith.
They will probably
be stalled for at least a month...
I still have my duties to complete.
Excuse me.
Hey!
What an insolent attitude!
How much is the damage?
No big deal.
I see.
It's thanks to how well
our rear guard held out...
...the enemy could hardly get close to us.
He handled a group of
heavy cavalrymen all by himself...
...even though it was on
a straight road in the woods.
He really is something.
Rickert!
Where is Guts?
He sent me on ahead.
I hope he's still alive.
It's time for me to go back...
Damn it!
I screwed up...
Griffith!
Grab my hand!
Retreat!
D-Don't let them get away!
Why did you come back here?
Don't talk!
You'll bite your tongue!
This is no good!
They'll catch us because
we're double mounted!
Hang on!
We're almost to the edge of the woods!
Ready!
Disperse!
What?
Fire!
R-Retreat!
Retreat!
At any rate, it was
amazing the way Guts fought.
Just as Griffith expected,
he has what it takes.
By the way, Guts is nowhere to be found.
Despite his age...
...Griffith has the qualities of a great leader...
...and the others rely on him completely.
Besides that, he's got perfect judgment...
...and he knows how to take decisive action...
He's more than just
the leader of a mercenary band...
Mr. Guts...
What are you doing?
Are you cooling off up here?
Thanks for your help before.
I narrowly escaped because of you.
I'm Rickert.
I really admire you.
I have never seen anyone who is...
...such an amazing fighter,
except for Mr. Griffith.
I have done nothing but my duty.
I have no reason to be thanked.
The same thing goes for you.
Well, I'm not going
to argue with you about it.
Anyway, come with us.
A party isn't as lively without the hero.
A feast is being held, partly as a welcome.
I-I never asked for anything like that!
W-What are you doing?
Don't touch me!
Don't be shy.
L-Let go of me!
Hey, here he comes.
P-Put me down, you big-headed bastard!
I am Pippin.
Y-You.
Drink.
Everyone!
Let's drink in celebration
of our brash, new friend!
I give you real credit, rookie!
You're pretty impressive!
You cut off the enemy's attack all
by yourself, even when outnumbered!
As Griffith thought, you have what it takes!
Sure, you've got some issues,
but it's good to have you on board!
Let's kick back, rookie!
That bastard...
Looking back, the morning comes.
Don't find your face in your glass.
Take the moonlight by the tail.
It's a rainy sight. You're shading.
What is that?
It's just the same.
What is trying your crown?
I'm spending my glass, walking back.
So wear my glass. You're fading.
I'm waiting so long.
I'm waiting...